<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pondering Life on Robert Xu</title>
    <link>https://www.robxu9.com/tags/pondering-life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pondering Life on Robert Xu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2014-2016 Robert Xu. All Rights Reserved. Content not indicative of any addl party.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 22:48:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.robxu9.com/tags/pondering-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>oh god what am I doing</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/12/oh-god-what-am-i-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 22:48:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/12/oh-god-what-am-i-doing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, December. The time of year where there&amp;rsquo;s a surprising lack of snow on the
ground, finals are over surprisingly early, and time for pondering life has
become plentiful. Which brings me to pondering life and my decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What on earth am I doing? Where will I be after I graduate? What do I want to
do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial thought was to go and try to pursue a MBA, because that&amp;rsquo;s useful and
all, but somewhere along the line I saw all the applications and became less
enthusiastic. Then I thought about the possibility that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get into
graduate school because I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough work experience, and lo and behold,
I&amp;rsquo;m searching for jobs again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(To Eric, my mentor at Amazon: you&amp;rsquo;re right, you win.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But really, &lt;strong&gt;what am I doing?&lt;/strong&gt; I think the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m graduating early has
me stuttering a bit, because that&amp;rsquo;s something big and not ordinary by any means.
I was going to brush it off by saying I&amp;rsquo;d pad that year out with the MBA, but
the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m stuttering on even that has made me realise that I really
should stop and think, and not mindlessly toil through the semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mum suggested that I should do a dual math major; I responded by pointing
out that I&amp;rsquo;d still graduate a semester early because that only pads out
how many credits by about 4-5 courses. So it doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve the lingering
thoughts in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still haven&amp;rsquo;t answered the question, so I suppose I should do that first.
I&amp;rsquo;m trying to complete my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science in an exemplary
way. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to rush through it (though, I suppose in some aspects I
already have), and I want good grades in CS, damnit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where will I be after I graduate?&lt;/strong&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t know. Amazon&amp;rsquo;s a possibility; but
I never really had time to think about it this semester. (Note to self: do not
take so many project courses at once.) Enrolling into graduate school is another
possibility. I have to do a bunch of job applications, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, all possibilities, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. &lt;em&gt;And that uncertainty is killing
me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, there&amp;rsquo;s only one way to find out, I suppose. Time to apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do I want to do?&lt;/strong&gt; Well, I want to program, of course. Whether I want to
work at a startup, at a major company, work on my own projects, etc&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not
too sure right now. But hey, I guess it all builds up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the end of this blog post is still &amp;ldquo;what am I even doing&amp;rdquo;. In the end, though,
I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s how it&amp;rsquo;ll always be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>