<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robert Xu</title>
    <link>https://www.robxu9.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Robert Xu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2014-2017 Robert Xu. All Rights Reserved. Content not indicative of any addl party.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 01:27:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.robxu9.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Swedish Conspiracy</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/the-swedish-conspiracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 01:27:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/the-swedish-conspiracy/</guid>
      <description>There is no Swedish conspiracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2017/08/hello-world-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 01:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2017/08/hello-world-part-3/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a bit eerie to learn that I last updated this two years ago.
In a way, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been surprised; 2016 was a hectic year for me, whether it was making sure that I passed my classes outstandingly (and mostly succeeded), or looking at jobs (spoiler - I just passed my one year mark at Amazon, excluding my internship), apartment hunting, time with friends, Overwatch coming out, and just general travelling&amp;hellip; despite the fact that my blog was always on my laptop I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the motivation to pull it out and update it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>do cleanups, not rewrites</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2016/02/do-cleanups-not-rewrites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 19:49:28 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2016/02/do-cleanups-not-rewrites/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had an application that&amp;rsquo;s been going on for about 3 years now. Kahinah was built to manage package updates for OpenMandriva Lx. I wrote it, did incremental updates to it, declared it a horrible mess and that I would rewrite it. Then never touched it for nearly two years.
The problem with rewrites is that you&amp;rsquo;re going into the mentality that you&amp;rsquo;re going to throw away all your code and restart from scratch; consequently, you can redo the whole structure of your app, make it all nice, neat, and everything looks nice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>oh god what am I doing</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/12/oh-god-what-am-i-doing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 22:48:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/12/oh-god-what-am-i-doing/</guid>
      <description>Ah, December. The time of year where there&amp;rsquo;s a surprising lack of snow on the ground, finals are over surprisingly early, and time for pondering life has become plentiful. Which brings me to pondering life and my decisions.
What on earth am I doing? Where will I be after I graduate? What do I want to do?
My initial thought was to go and try to pursue a MBA, because that&amp;rsquo;s useful and all, but somewhere along the line I saw all the applications and became less enthusiastic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a tribute to Dr. Doran</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/a-tribute-to-dr.-doran/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 21:00:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/a-tribute-to-dr.-doran/</guid>
      <description>(x-posted from my facebook)
(function(d, s, id) { var js, fjs = d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0]; if (d.getElementById(id)) return; js = d.createElement(s); js.id = id; js.src = &#34;//connect.facebook.net/en_GB/sdk.js#xfbml=1&amp;version=v2.3&#34;; fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js, fjs);}(document, &#39;script&#39;, &#39;facebook-jssdk&#39;));On Wednesday, 19 August, around midday, many of us learned that our long time high school principal, Dr. Michael Doran,...
Posted by Robert Xu on&amp;nbsp;Wednesday, 19 August 2015 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>where have I been all summer?</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/where-have-i-been-all-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 03:17:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/where-have-i-been-all-summer/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering why all the posts have suddenly appeared, the answer is that I&amp;rsquo;ve finally achieved peak boredom level that I need to write on my blog again.
That was quick. I just flew in from Seattle today.
So if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t obvious from the description, I just finished an internship this past week. I already find myself wishing I could be back at my internship with Amazon - it was amazing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new domains</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/new-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 03:11:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/new-domains/</guid>
      <description>So.
Over the past two months I have expanded my domain acquisitions. I now own rxu.io and rxu.tech, but I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly have too much of a clue with what to do with them. Yet.
I&amp;rsquo;m thinking that I&amp;rsquo;ll be making rxu.io my personal homepage site - some nice one page with links to all my profiles, resumes, this blog, etc; and rxu.tech a listing of projects that I am or were involved with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>may, june, july, and august music</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/may-june-july-and-august-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 02:05:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/may-june-july-and-august-music/</guid>
      <description>long time no see, blog.
nothing new on the music front - I did listen to a lot of BBC Radio 1 and Capital FM London, though. So most of my music from these past few months come from there.
Honestly, I think I was just really lazy to go and find really new and fresh music. That might have been because my apartment-mate for the summer, Theo, had a bunch of interesting music on him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>graduating early</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/04/graduating-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 16:32:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/04/graduating-early/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s weird to think that only a few semesters ago, I was starting university. But as I went into my advisor last week and sat down and went over my coursework and transcript, I noticed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how many more classes I needed.
So we both sat down and analysed what I had left to take, and what I was planning to take. And we both came to the conclusion that I would be graduating one year early.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>march/april music</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/04/march/april-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 16:27:43 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/04/march/april-music/</guid>
      <description>I got Spotify Premium this month! So everything I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to is in my Spotify playlist.
A criticism of Spotify here - your new client sucks. It takes up double the memory, meaning I can&amp;rsquo;t run it and use my Linux VM, I can&amp;rsquo;t Ctrl-F through my playlist anymore, and your playlist has started to remove tracks on its own.
Not cool. I don&amp;rsquo;t like tracks disappearing from my playlist because they&amp;rsquo;re either local files or unplayable on this computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>and now for something completely different</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/03/and-now-for-something-completely-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 20:28:53 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/03/and-now-for-something-completely-different/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s spring break, and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to finally have a week to kind of relax and not worry about midterms as much (of course, I&amp;rsquo;m ignoring the fact that I have a midterm in CSE306/Operating Systems next week), but it also gives the chance to reflect and ask, &amp;ldquo;what the hell went wrong on Friday?&amp;rdquo;
Friday was my CSE320/Computer Organization &amp;amp; Architecture midterm - a midterm that currently has a 43% average and what the professor called &amp;ldquo;dismal scores across the board&amp;rdquo;: so where did it all go wrong?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cloudflare&#39;d</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/03/cloudflared/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 22:11:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/03/cloudflared/</guid>
      <description>My website was just cloudflare&amp;rsquo;d today.
In a nutshell, this means that I&amp;rsquo;ve switched nameservers (again), from DigitalOcean to CloudFlare. The main reason for that is because of CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s free https support, which I use in tandem with Github Pages.
(Yes, no https on robxu9.com severely irked me.)
Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with new mail hosting lately, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been switching mail providers like&amp;hellip; every other week. Still self hosting in the end, but I just wanted to remark on a few things:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>february music</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/02/february-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 23:55:44 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/02/february-music/</guid>
      <description>One of my more boring months. Other than the following, I&amp;rsquo;ve just been listening to BBC Radio 1, BBC Radio 2, Captial FM London, FRESH 102.7, or HOT 99.5&amp;hellip;
 The Script - a still amazing band, with their song &amp;ldquo;Man on a Wire&amp;rdquo;.
 BoA - because I can&amp;rsquo;t have a normal playlist without some J-Pop or K-Pop - although, the K-Pop is relatively recent, and I still prefer J-Pop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>welp</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/02/welp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 23:46:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/02/welp/</guid>
      <description>That was quick.
What have I been up to? Things I&amp;rsquo;ve done lately include:
 studying for CSE 320, which is System Architecture. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m slow on the uptake with this class, whatnot with muxes and ALUs&amp;hellip;
 working on CSE 306, which is implementing a simple grep without libc. So just Linux system calls. Not bad, just time consuming. Also I gave up trying to make descriptive errors and just dumped errno.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sophomore year, take two</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/sophomore-year-take-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 17:54:17 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/sophomore-year-take-two/</guid>
      <description>Long story short:
 CSE 306: Operating Systems CSE 312: Ethics CSE 320: System Architecture MEC 280: Pollution &amp;amp; Human Health CCS 202: Film Genres  I hope I survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kahinah, take two</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/kahinah-take-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 14:25:16 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/kahinah-take-two/</guid>
      <description>This one was the one that needed the obvious rewrite.
Background Kahinah is an updates manager for the OpenMandriva Association&amp;rsquo;s distribution, OpenMandriva Lx. Its goal is to monitor builds that are produced from a build system (which is abf.io right now), and create a karma system which testers can vote on the updates, and eventually accept them as working, or reject them as deficient.
This worked for the most part, but when it came time for a large number of builds (think a KDE SC 4 version update), Kahinah was overwhelmed, testers were crushed, and updates had a hard time going through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>january music</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/january-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 14:04:50 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/january-music/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to a bunch of new things lately:
 PVRIS - a relatively new band that I discovered via BBC radio one. they have really great songs, especially &amp;ldquo;My House&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;St. Patrick&amp;rdquo;. It feels a bit like Paramore, although the sound is much more edgy.
 30 Seconds To Mars - I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to them for a while now actually, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten tired of their songs yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>duplex in C, take two</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/duplex-in-c-take-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:09:29 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/duplex-in-c-take-two/</guid>
      <description>I seem to be doing a bunch of rewrites of my older projects nowadays. But sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s necessary. It is for the case of duplex (and libduplex).
Background When I was working at DigitalOcean over the past summer, my main project was a communication framework called duplex. Duplex&amp;rsquo;s aim was to create a simple messaging framework that could potentially be used for RPC. The first version was prototyped in Go, and I created libdpx, which was the first version in C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>robxu9.com, take two</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/robxu9.com-take-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 22:48:42 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/robxu9.com-take-two/</guid>
      <description>I never had the time to really blog about things in length after I left DigitalOcean. I guess I felt like it was time consuming and such effort could better be spent sleeping or coding or something along the lines of that.
But then school came around and I was thrown into the chaos that is the fall semester of university, and I never had a chance to step back from all the craziness that followed and put my thoughts together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>valgrind is important</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/08/valgrind-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/08/valgrind-is-important/</guid>
      <description>Most people have heard of debugging tools like gdb. For the rest, it&amp;rsquo;s usually just continuous testing and catching problems with your eye. But sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s not that simple.
Take for example (and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this example a lot), libdpx. I was trying to clean up the code for the past two days, but when I moved a simple statement that should work, everything essentially went to hell. You can see that commit here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stdout is slow</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/08/stdout-is-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/08/stdout-is-slow/</guid>
      <description>Reading or writing any sort of stream can be slow. I cannot stress how much that is true.
It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly noticeable, especially when you have some sort of GUI program in debug mode and it prints out a load of stuff. Each printout, whether it&amp;rsquo;s piped somewhere else or goes to the console, can add time that matters to your program&amp;rsquo;s execution.
Why bring it up now? Take for example, libdpx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ctypes, Why?</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/07/ctypes-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/07/ctypes-why/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t claim to be a particularly good Python programmer at all. I&amp;rsquo;m probably one of the&amp;hellip; less useful people to program Python - I much prefer Go (and to be rather honest, C).
But I think I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered the nastiest piece of library I&amp;rsquo;ve used with Python - ctypes.
What is ctypes? It&amp;rsquo;s kind of like the psuedo C package for Go - it allows direct access to C functions and structures and all those nice things, and lets you use C libraries in your Python program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Blog.</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/07/hello-blog./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/07/hello-blog./</guid>
      <description>Welp, I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s about time that I made an actual blog on my actual domain. Whee!
I made a list of projects I wanted to do in the future - kinda like my personal project collection. When I actually compiled the list, though, it started to become a bit unrealistic.
 uitest - UI testing via VNC connection gomq - MineQuest, written in Go kahinah - OpenMandriva&amp;rsquo;s QA Bot, which needs a rewrite (codenamed v4) aye - a DO API client in Go (like tugboat) gnome 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey, I&amp;rsquo;m Robert. Supposedly an about page is supposed to be a window into a person&amp;rsquo;s world. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s a horrifying thought, so let&amp;rsquo;s make sure never to go down there.
Instead, let me tell you about myself. New Yorker for the first half of my childhood; Marylander for the second half. Graduated with a BS in Computer Science from Stony Brook University (2013-2016!), and now I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer at Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>