<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robert Xu</title>
    <link>https://www.robxu9.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Robert Xu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2014-2015 Robert Xu. All Rights Reserved. Content not indicative of any addl party.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 22:11:30 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.robxu9.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>cloudflare&#39;d</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/03/cloudflared/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 22:11:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/03/cloudflared/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My website was just cloudflare&amp;rsquo;d today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, this means that I&amp;rsquo;ve switched nameservers (again), from
DigitalOcean to CloudFlare. The main reason for that is because of
CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s free https support, which I use in tandem with Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Yes, no https on robxu9.com severely irked me.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with new mail hosting lately, so
I&amp;rsquo;ve been switching mail providers like&amp;hellip; every other week. Still self
hosting in the end, but I just wanted to remark on a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zentyal&lt;/strong&gt;: I &lt;em&gt;really really really really really really&lt;/em&gt; wanted to
like you like Carly Rae Jepsen&amp;rsquo;s new obsession. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. You have a
strange number of problems, your general configuration screen doesn&amp;rsquo;t work
(&amp;ldquo;missing parameter: id&amp;rdquo;???), and it was an overall mess. But your ability
to mimic Exchange and also put together Mail, Contacts, and Calendar all
in one with OpenChange and SoGo was really appealing. Unfortunately, errors
aren&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mailinabox.email&lt;/strong&gt;: I mentioned that I wanted to use CloudFlare, right?
Mail-in-a-Box is really insistent that you use its internal DNS, and if you
don&amp;rsquo;t, add 100000000 DNS records to CloudFlare instead. That&amp;rsquo;s not really an
issue, but then bind9 refused to resolve any DNS requests, and I gave up there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yunohost&lt;/strong&gt;: I really wish I had a picture of that meme right now. But this
is what I&amp;rsquo;m currently using now, after three weeks (Mail-in-a-Box is actually
still up on my other VPS, but that&amp;rsquo;s going down as soon as DNS propagates).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; nice to have a tiled welcome screen and something that seems to
Just Work &amp;trade; after so long. Although, I have to admit, Dovecot ran out of
epoll handlers and that left me stumped, but a reboot solved that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should go study for CSE 320 now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>february music</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/02/february-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 23:55:44 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/02/february-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my more boring months. Other than the following, I&amp;rsquo;ve just been
listening to BBC Radio 1, BBC Radio 2, Captial FM London, FRESH 102.7,
or HOT 99.5&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Script&lt;/em&gt; - a still amazing band, with their song &amp;ldquo;Man on a Wire&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BoA&lt;/em&gt; - because I can&amp;rsquo;t have a normal playlist without some J-Pop or
K-Pop - although, the K-Pop is relatively recent, and I still prefer J-Pop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OneRepublic&lt;/em&gt; - I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what &amp;ldquo;I Lived&amp;rdquo; was until
now, even though it&amp;rsquo;s been playing literally everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;David Guetta&lt;/em&gt; - From his album &lt;em&gt;Listen (Deluxe)&lt;/em&gt;, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard
really played on any radio station at all recently. But &amp;ldquo;Dangerous&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;What I Did For Love&amp;rdquo; are really nice songs, even though &amp;ldquo;What I Did For Love&amp;rdquo;
was &amp;ldquo;very gospel&amp;rsquo;y&amp;rdquo;, according to my friend (I like it, though!).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sia&lt;/em&gt; - &amp;ldquo;Elastic Heart&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Bang My Head&amp;rdquo; are two amazing songs - sure, it&amp;rsquo;s
a bit hard to understand her through her Australia accent, but you can&amp;rsquo;t deny
that her voice is amazing. And then when you realise that she doesn&amp;rsquo;t show her
face at any performance and that it&amp;rsquo;s all her voice, it just makes it all the
more remarkable at her success. You can truly appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah. Boring tracks. Recommendations? Let me know below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>welp</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/02/welp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 23:46:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/02/welp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That was quick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have I been up to? Things I&amp;rsquo;ve done lately include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;studying for CSE 320, which is System Architecture. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m slow on
the uptake with this class, whatnot with muxes and ALUs&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;working on CSE 306, which is implementing a simple &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; without libc. So
just Linux system calls. Not bad, just time consuming. Also I gave up trying
to make descriptive errors and just dumped &lt;code&gt;errno.h&lt;/code&gt; into a switch statement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I should probably do the Ethics project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beat Tales of Symphonia, Tales of Symphonia: Knights of Ratatosk, and started
Tales of the Abyss, then realised that I actually have homework to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Had an Amazon interview. This was my first real interview in a &lt;strong&gt;LONG&lt;/strong&gt; time,
and I&amp;rsquo;m not so certain I ace&amp;rsquo;d it. It was an experience, but it took my brain
way too long to warm up and I think that cost me. I think I missed a Big-O
notation and I definitely forgot about Kruskal&amp;rsquo;s algorithm. Shit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Went to Boston for ECAASU 2015! Here&amp;rsquo;s a tip: don&amp;rsquo;t drive in Boston. The
roads make no sense whatsoever (they&amp;rsquo;re like downtown Manhattan), and the
random forks and roundabouts hurt my head.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more happening soon, but I gotta survive until at least Spring Break&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sophomore year, take two</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/sophomore-year-take-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 17:54:17 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/sophomore-year-take-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long story short:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CSE 306: Operating Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CSE 312: Ethics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CSE 320: System Architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MEC 280: Pollution &amp;amp; Human Health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CCS 202: Film Genres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I survive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kahinah, take two</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/kahinah-take-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 14:25:16 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/kahinah-take-two/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This one was the one that needed the obvious rewrite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;background:226c55525206653d6c71e0f5695b4e16&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kahinah is an updates manager for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://openmandriva.org&#34;&gt;OpenMandriva&lt;/a&gt;
Association&amp;rsquo;s distribution, OpenMandriva Lx. Its goal is to monitor builds that
are produced from a build system (which is &lt;a href=&#34;https://abf.io&#34;&gt;abf.io&lt;/a&gt; right now),
and create a karma system which testers can vote on the updates, and eventually
accept them as working, or reject them as deficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This worked for the most part, but when it came time for a large number of
builds (think a KDE SC 4 version update), Kahinah was overwhelmed, testers
were crushed, and updates had a hard time going through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the system suffered from numerous bugs due to changes on abf.io,
and it certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t help that I was using &lt;a href=&#34;http://beego.me&#34;&gt;beego&lt;/a&gt; and
pulling many many dependencies, which shot build times up through the roof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-4:226c55525206653d6c71e0f5695b4e16&#34;&gt;Version&amp;hellip; 4?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first couple of versions were just getting it usable and bearable for the
most part. This rewrite is entirely from scratch, with no existing code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally provide a decent JSON API, and I plan to use JSON web tokens to
provide authentication (thanks Matt for pointing that out). Updates are now
more organized, and for the first time ever, I&amp;rsquo;m providing a new type called
advisories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-advisories:226c55525206653d6c71e0f5695b4e16&#34;&gt;What are Advisories?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advisories are groups of updates. Instead of voting on one update, we create
an advisory with the updates we want to contain in it. They can range from
just one update to a group of them, and testers can test ALL of them at the
same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has two purposes - one, to force package maintainers to document more
throughly for corporate customers (for example, putting bug references so
that Kahinah can connect to Bugzilla and say, hey, here&amp;rsquo;s a possible solution
that you can test), and two, to make large updates much more manageable for
testers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also brings us in line with practically every distribution out there
that has to keep track of updates (like Fedora&amp;rsquo;s bodhi).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-else-has-changed:226c55525206653d6c71e0f5695b4e16&#34;&gt;What else has changed?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The frontend is separate from the backend, and is written with
&lt;a href=&#34;http://emberjs.com&#34;&gt;ember.js&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s my first foray into ember.js, and I&amp;rsquo;m
curious to see how it goes. The documentation is a bit random, especially since
it looks like they&amp;rsquo;re migrating towards some ES6 standards, so it&amp;rsquo;ll be
both a learning experience and a headache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;release-soon:226c55525206653d6c71e0f5695b4e16&#34;&gt;Release soon?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I get stuff working, maybe. I intend to deploy a beta version to
replace the current Kahinah on jasper sometime at the end of this month
or the beginning of next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;github:226c55525206653d6c71e0f5695b4e16&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robxu9/kahinah/tree/dev_nobeego&#34;&gt;kahinah&lt;/a&gt; is licensed
under the MIT license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>january music</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/january-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 14:04:50 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/january-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to a bunch of new things lately:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PVRIS&lt;/em&gt; - a relatively new band that I discovered via BBC radio one.
they have really great songs, especially &amp;ldquo;My House&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;St. Patrick&amp;rdquo;.
It feels a bit like Paramore, although the sound is much more edgy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;30 Seconds To Mars&lt;/em&gt; - I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to them for a while now actually,
but I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten tired of their songs yet. &amp;ldquo;Kings and Queens&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;This is
War&amp;rdquo; top my playlist for January.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paramore&lt;/em&gt; - Still on my playlist. But just &amp;ldquo;Part II&amp;rdquo;, now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Calvin Harris feat. Ellie Goulding&lt;/em&gt; - &amp;ldquo;Outside&amp;rdquo; is the newest of the Calvin
Harris and Ellie Goulding combos, with a more negative light on relationships
in the lyrics. I wonder if that had anything to do with both of their breakups?
Nevertheless, an enjoyable song.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fall Out Boy&lt;/em&gt; - &amp;ldquo;Centuries&amp;rdquo;, which is becoming the most overplayed song on
every single radio station in the New York area. Can&amp;rsquo;t deny it&amp;rsquo;s catchy, but
it&amp;rsquo;s getting tiring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ayumi Hamasaki&lt;/em&gt; - This is because I recently played through Tales of Xillia
and Tales of Xilla 2, both of which are outstanding games (though I enjoyed
Xillia 2 more because it actually made me cry). &amp;ldquo;progress&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Song 4 u&amp;rdquo; are
the opening songs of both of those games respectively, and I like the way
especially in &amp;ldquo;progress&amp;rdquo; that the instrumentals were played. Screw the lyrics,
the force in that sound!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BUMP OF CHICKEN&lt;/em&gt; - I also played Tales of the Abyss recently (though not as
recently as Tales of Xillia (2)), and since I had Hamasaki&amp;rsquo;s songs on my phone,
I thought, why not? Let&amp;rsquo;s add &amp;ldquo;カルマ&amp;rdquo; to that, too. (That&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;KARMA&amp;rdquo; in
English.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Song recomendations? Soundcloud things I should listen to? Let me know in the
comments below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>duplex in C, take two</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/duplex-in-c-take-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:09:29 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/duplex-in-c-take-two/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I seem to be doing a bunch of rewrites of my older projects nowadays. But
sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s necessary. It is for the case of duplex (and libduplex).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;background:dbd361d9d83ece52b494a1b526aef755&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was working at DigitalOcean over the past summer, my main project was
a communication framework called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/progrium/duplex&#34;&gt;duplex&lt;/a&gt;.
Duplex&amp;rsquo;s aim was to create a simple messaging framework that could potentially
be used for RPC. The first version was prototyped in Go, and I created
&lt;code&gt;libdpx&lt;/code&gt;, which was the first version in C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, &lt;code&gt;libdpx&lt;/code&gt; had some major flaws - I didn&amp;rsquo;t use a proper build
system, I used &lt;code&gt;libtask&lt;/code&gt; for coroutines (switching that out with &lt;code&gt;lthread&lt;/code&gt;,
then switching back to &lt;code&gt;libtask&lt;/code&gt; after &lt;code&gt;lthread&lt;/code&gt; didn&amp;rsquo;t work with shared
libraries), and in general I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage memory well. You could lose data
along the way with the race conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeff realised that a lot of the things we wanted to implement with duplex
would be hard, because essentially we were creating a new protocol. So
recently, he took to creating a second version in Go, but this time
sitting on top of the SSH protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SSH protocol provides a bunch of the logic so that we don&amp;rsquo;t have to
worry about it - authentication, security, and channel management. This
was our way of wrapping it in a user friendly form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;libduplex:dbd361d9d83ece52b494a1b526aef755&#34;&gt;libduplex&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;libduplex&lt;/code&gt; is the second version of duplex in C. However, this time, I&amp;rsquo;m
being extra careful to, essentially, not fuck up the threading. This time
there are no lightweight coroutines or &lt;code&gt;libtask&lt;/code&gt;; instead, I directly call
pthreads in order to manage calls. The API is still threadsafe, and I still
run a thread dedicated to each ssh session (because libssh does not support
multiple threads working on sessions, which is understandable given the
complexity of the task - but it does have a non-blocking mode, and I rely
on that). Currently you can bind to tcp and unix sockets, and if any other
reliable protocol becomes available, I will gladly implement that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intent behind this is to make the Go version and C version be fully
compatible. I will not &lt;code&gt;cgo&lt;/code&gt; these bindings this time, because that seems
like a poor idea if they&amp;rsquo;re both going to be the same - the pure Go version
would work better in Go. However, there is an interest in making a Python
version for libduplex, which I will get around to after &lt;code&gt;libduplex&lt;/code&gt; is
fully compatible with the already existing Go counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;managing-time:dbd361d9d83ece52b494a1b526aef755&#34;&gt;Managing Time&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last duplex suffered immensely from a lack of manpower - Jeff has his
own projects and clients to focus on, and I have university which I have
to concentrate on. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t intend to abandon this at all - if
possible, I&amp;rsquo;d like this second version to become the main version of duplex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to take duplex further, too. Not just for standard communication
and RPC between applications, but further into plugin systems, APIs over
the internet, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I definitely want to keep working on it despite university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(You can make my life slightly easier by making pull requests.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-from-here:dbd361d9d83ece52b494a1b526aef755&#34;&gt;Where from here?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going from here remains to be seen. My immediate priorities are getting
libduplex off the ground so that it can be at least used in a beta state.
Maybe even declare it 1.0 if it gets to be good enough without any major
flaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m heading along for the ride and I definitely want to see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;github:dbd361d9d83ece52b494a1b526aef755&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robxu9/libduplex&#34;&gt;libduplex&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under the MIT
license. See &lt;code&gt;HACKING&lt;/code&gt; for building instructions and more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>robxu9.com, take two</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/robxu9.com-take-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 22:48:42 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/robxu9.com-take-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never had the time to really blog about things in length after I left
DigitalOcean. I guess I felt like it was time consuming and such effort could
better be spent sleeping or coding or something along the lines of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then school came around and I was thrown into the chaos that is the fall
semester of university, and I never had a chance to step back from all the
craziness that followed and put my thoughts together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now here we are. It&amp;rsquo;s 2015, almost 6 months since my last blog post.
I&amp;rsquo;ve resolved to take more time out to reflect on what&amp;rsquo;s been happening and
gather my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m therefore taking bets on how quickly this will fall apart. Minimum time
after I finish writing this post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>valgrind is important</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/08/valgrind-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/08/valgrind-is-important/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Most people have heard of debugging tools like &lt;code&gt;gdb&lt;/code&gt;. For the rest, it&amp;rsquo;s
usually just continuous testing and catching problems with your eye. But
sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s not that simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take for example (and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this example &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt;), &lt;code&gt;libdpx&lt;/code&gt;. I was
trying to clean up the code for the past two days, but when I moved a simple
statement that should work, everything essentially went to hell. You can see
that commit &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robxu9/duplex/commit/663bb6de4b52930d1a14
ee86777f69eb1d2f9d99#diff-53207fdef530e854ec6cdb342eef1970R120&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, the
&lt;code&gt;alchanfree()&lt;/code&gt; method is commented because if I tried to &lt;code&gt;chanfree()&lt;/code&gt;,
segfaults would be everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t look bad - we&amp;rsquo;re initialising a new channel, then
sending the frame to the write frames method. Then we wait for something to
come back. Because of cooperative threading, everything should work just
dandily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I uncommented the &lt;code&gt;alchanfree()&lt;/code&gt; method, stuff didn&amp;rsquo;t work. And I was
utterly confused. I was wondering why all of a sudden, I was getting segfaults
left and right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;enter-valgrind:8198804284f5f45e50df30e1088b1d71&#34;&gt;enter valgrind&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valgrind is this tool that not many people have heard of for some reason, yet
it is one of the most invaluable tools for memory checking that you could ever
have. It basically acts as a middle man between your program and libc,
catching &lt;code&gt;free/malloc/calloc/realloc&lt;/code&gt; calls and recording addresses, then
making sure whatever calls you &amp;lsquo;&lt;code&gt;alloc&lt;/code&gt; are &lt;code&gt;free&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;d later. As a result, it can
also detect reads and writes to &lt;code&gt;free&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;d pieces of memory, which would segfault
under normal conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But most people just ignore what &lt;code&gt;valgrind&lt;/code&gt; is saying. That&amp;rsquo;s bad. Don&amp;rsquo;t do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some sample output:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;==802== Memcheck, a memory error detector
==802== Copyright (C) 2002-2013, and GNU GPL&#39;d, by Julian Seward et al.
==802== Using Valgrind-3.9.0 and LibVEX; rerun with -h for copyright info
==802== Command: ./check_dpx
==802== 
==802== Syscall param timer_create(evp) points to uninitialised byte(s)
==802==    at 0x385AC03E72: timer_create@@GLIBC_2.3.3 (timer_create.c:82)
==802==    by 0x526E47B: srunner_run (check_run.c:407)
==802==    by 0x40361A: main (check.c:499)
==802==  Location 0xffefff750 is 0 bytes inside local_evp._sigev_un,
==802==  declared at timer_create.c:57, in frame #0 of thread 1
==802==  Uninitialised value was created by a stack allocation
==802==    at 0x3859015185: _dl_runtime_resolve (dl-trampoline.S:46)
==802== 
==830== HEAP SUMMARY:
==830==     in use at exit: 572,679 bytes in 96 blocks
==830==   total heap usage: 339 allocs, 243 frees, 1,510,826 bytes allocated
==830== 
==830== 3 bytes in 1 blocks are definitely lost in loss record 5 of 83
==830==    at 0x4A0645D: malloc (in /usr/lib64/valgrind/vgpreload_memcheck-amd64-linux.so)
==830==    by 0x4C1A428: _dpx_frame_msgpack_from (frame.c:171)
==830==    by 0x4C149DB: _dpx_duplex_conn_read_frames (conn.c:60)
==830==    by 0x4E5948B: taskstart (task.c:71)
==830==    by 0x38594479FF: ??? (in /usr/lib64/libc-2.18.so)
==830== 
==830== 72 bytes in 1 blocks are definitely lost in loss record 66 of 83
==830==    at 0x4A0645D: malloc (in /usr/lib64/valgrind/vgpreload_memcheck-amd64-linux.so)
==830==    by 0x4C174BD: dpx_frame_new (frame.c:27)
==830==    by 0x402700: test_dpx_call (check.c:224)
==830==    by 0x4029E6: test_dpx_rpc_call (check.c:279)
==830==    by 0x526E87D: srunner_run (check_run.c:396)
==830==    by 0x40361A: main (check.c:499)
==830== 
==830== 288 bytes in 1 blocks are possibly lost in loss record 72 of 83
==830==    at 0x4A081D4: calloc (in /usr/lib64/valgrind/vgpreload_memcheck-amd64-linux.so)
==830==    by 0x3859011C44: _dl_allocate_tls (dl-tls.c:296)
==830==    by 0x3859808862: pthread_create@@GLIBC_2.2.5 (allocatestack.c:580)
==830==    by 0x4C1BCD5: dpx_init (dpx.c:172)
==830==    by 0x4028F1: test_dpx_rpc_call (check.c:263)
==830==    by 0x526E87D: srunner_run (check_run.c:396)
==830==    by 0x40361A: main (check.c:499)
==830== 
==830== LEAK SUMMARY:
==830==    definitely lost: 75 bytes in 2 blocks
==830==    indirectly lost: 0 bytes in 0 blocks
==830==      possibly lost: 288 bytes in 1 blocks
==830==    still reachable: 572,316 bytes in 93 blocks
==830==         suppressed: 0 bytes in 0 blocks
==830== Reachable blocks (those to which a pointer was found) are not shown.
==830== To see them, rerun with: --leak-check=full --show-leak-kinds=all
==830== 
==830== For counts of detected and suppressed errors, rerun with: -v
==830== ERROR SUMMARY: 7 errors from 4 contexts (suppressed: 2 from 2)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that output looks, frankly, terrifying at first. But it&amp;rsquo;s actually not that
hard to interpret. It tells you how many blocks of memory it thinks are lost,
and where they were allocated. That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about output for invalid reads?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have those, because I rage&amp;hellip; obliterated them. Yes. That.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My problem was that something was trying to write to the channel after it was
free&amp;rsquo;d. That has now been solved, thanks to valgrind outputting 8 pages of
&amp;ldquo;invalid write of size 8, here (insert stacktrace), to a block that was free&amp;rsquo;d
here (insert stacktrace)&amp;ldquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;valgrind-treats-you-like-you-don-t-know-what-you-re-doing:8198804284f5f45e50df30e1088b1d71&#34;&gt;valgrind treats you like you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, that&amp;rsquo;s probably true. Manual memory management sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s good, because there&amp;rsquo;s definitely way more actual errors detected than
false positives. Case in point, here was my recycling bin after I printed out
my valgrind output and went through all of them one by one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.robxu9.com/media/2014-08-05-valgrind-is-important/2014-08-05 18.05.13
.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;so much paper...&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel old-fashioned because I do code reviews on paper, but hey, it&amp;rsquo;s easier
for me. I can&amp;rsquo;t be the only one who agrees&amp;hellip; right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;so-what-are-you-trying-to-tell-me:8198804284f5f45e50df30e1088b1d71&#34;&gt;so what are you trying to tell me&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valgrind your program. It&amp;rsquo;s good for detecting memory leaks and the likes of it
, can tell you when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to murder poor memory fields you don&amp;rsquo;t have
access to, and also other cool things. Really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll get you started! You can run valgrind with
&lt;code&gt;valgrind --leak-check=yes --read-var-info=yes --track-origins=yes ./[program]&lt;/code&gt;
and receive your lovely output. By default, valgrind prints to stderr. Redirect
it to stdout if you want to pipe it to &lt;code&gt;ansi2html&lt;/code&gt; or something similar to
to print it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-was-the-point-of-this-article:8198804284f5f45e50df30e1088b1d71&#34;&gt;what was the point of this article&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know, just that I had a problem, used Valgrind, solved said problem?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stdout is slow</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/08/stdout-is-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/08/stdout-is-slow/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Reading or writing any sort of stream can be slow.  I cannot stress how much
that is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly noticeable, especially when you have some sort of GUI program
in debug mode and it prints out a load of stuff. Each printout, whether it&amp;rsquo;s
piped somewhere else or goes to the console, can add time that matters to your
program&amp;rsquo;s execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-bring-it-up-now:8e44ed532c74307615cde872e9d5796a&#34;&gt;Why bring it up now?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take for example, &lt;code&gt;libdpx&lt;/code&gt;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t silenced any of the debug output; rather
I use it to my advantage so that I can trace where things are going. I&amp;rsquo;ve
caught several rather significant bugs this way, since tracing with &lt;code&gt;gdb&lt;/code&gt; is
rather hard on a coroutine library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what about performance?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&#34;http://zeromq.org/results:perf-howto&#34;&gt;ØMQ&lt;/a&gt;, their performance in
terms of latency (which is the only one I have tested with duplex) for 100000
1-byte messages is a mere 30.9 microseconds, a figure I was able to replicate
locally. Jeff mentioned that I could look into performance with &lt;code&gt;libdpx&lt;/code&gt;, and I
said &amp;ldquo;sure, why not?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tests are practically identical to the ØMQ ones - I have a receiver and a
sender of messages. And what I got initially stunned me:
{% highlight shell-session %}
$ ./send_lat 127.0.0.1 9999 1 100000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;lots-of-stdout-here:8e44ed532c74307615cde872e9d5796a&#34;&gt;lots of stdout here&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;message size: 1 bytes
message count: 100000
avg latency: 6788597.849 nanoseconds
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s 6788.6 microseconds. Yikes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;save-the-output-for-debugging-only:8e44ed532c74307615cde872e9d5796a&#34;&gt;save the output for debugging only&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went ahead today and created a &lt;code&gt;DEBUG_FUNC(...)&lt;/code&gt; macro, which &lt;code&gt;#ifdef DEBUG&lt;/code&gt;
would actually execute anything inside the function, and if not, would delete
anything there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then I wrapped all my not-important &lt;code&gt;printf&lt;/code&gt; statements with &lt;code&gt;DEBUG_FUNC&lt;/code&gt;,
and the errors I separated out into &lt;code&gt;fprintf(stderr, ...)&lt;/code&gt;. And then what did
I find?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% highlight shell-session %}
$ ./send_lat 127.0.0.1 9999 1 100000
message size: 1 bytes
message count: 100000
avg latency: 129588.328 nanoseconds
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;129.6 microseconds. A huge improvement. And because I didn&amp;rsquo;t write to stdout at
all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing-means-disk-i-o:8e44ed532c74307615cde872e9d5796a&#34;&gt;writing means disk i/o&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is particularly true for anything - if you write to anything, there is
going to be overhead because of flushing the stream to disk or wherever it
wants to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that advice about writing to files in C? You have to flush the stream
before closing it, or changes aren&amp;rsquo;t written to disk. It&amp;rsquo;s the same thing with
&lt;code&gt;stdout&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;code&gt;stdout&lt;/code&gt; is a file, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because files like &lt;code&gt;stdout&lt;/code&gt; are line buffered by default - so anything
will stay in the buffer until it hits a newline, at which point the program
essentially pauses to force everything to the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From what I know, there are three types of buffering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No buffering, so anything written will be flushed immediately to disk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Block buffering, so after a certain length or manual call it will flush.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line buffering, so after a &lt;code&gt;\n&lt;/code&gt; it will flush.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A note here that was made on &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/a/171662
1/438175&#34;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; is that &lt;code&gt;stderr&lt;/code&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t buffered because it&amp;rsquo;s standard error - so
naturally it wants to get the error to you as quickly as possible, even if it
means slowing down everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can set any stream&amp;rsquo;s buffering characteristics with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cplusplus.com/reference/cstdio/setvbuf/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;setvbuf()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - either full buffering,
line buffering, or no buffering. Practically all files are opened with
full buffering (hence the advice to flush before you close), while files like
&lt;code&gt;stdout&lt;/code&gt; are line buffered, and &lt;code&gt;stderr&lt;/code&gt; is not even buffered at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that flushing takes CPU cycles. It has to empty out the buffer by writing
it to disk, an operation that is costly because it&amp;rsquo;s disk i/o, and then it
has to clear the buffer before it can resume execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While SSDs speed up disk i/o by a noticeable margin, not everyone has SSDs. So
just please don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;code&gt;printf&lt;/code&gt; in your library. It makes an impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-should-i-handle-logging-then-in-a-high-performance-application:8e44ed532c74307615cde872e9d5796a&#34;&gt;how should I handle logging then in a high performance application?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a difficult topic. Some of my suggestions in the past have been to
write on a dedicated thread; that is, print whatever you need but only flush
on a dedicated thread, so that way that thread is the slow one while the
others can continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I guess I would mention that it really depends on what you&amp;rsquo;re making.
Sometimes, forwarding any output to a logging server might be better. Maybe
block buffering instead of line buffering &lt;code&gt;stdout&lt;/code&gt;. Write your own functions.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some interesting ones have been making a channel across threads, and then
sending log messages that are marked with your thread name &amp;amp; time to another
thread to be finally processed and outputted, where in a worker thread:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% highlight go %}
mylog.Send(fmt.Sprintf(&amp;ldquo;my logging message&amp;rdquo;))
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which sends it through a channel to the logging thread, which then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% highlight go %}
for log := range logChan {
    fmt.Printf(&amp;ldquo;%s %s: %s\n&amp;rdquo;, log.Time, log.Threadname, log.Message)
}
{% endhighlight %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or something like that. Again, I really guess it depends on what you want to
do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ctypes, Why?</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/07/ctypes-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/07/ctypes-why/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t claim to be a particularly good Python programmer at all. I&amp;rsquo;m probably
one of the&amp;hellip; less useful people to program Python - I much prefer Go (and to
be rather honest, C).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered the nastiest piece of library I&amp;rsquo;ve used with
Python - &lt;code&gt;ctypes&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-is-ctypes:999b5b7440fa538dd5d40514f7485df6&#34;&gt;What is &lt;code&gt;ctypes&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of like the psuedo &lt;code&gt;C&lt;/code&gt; package for Go - it allows direct access to
C functions and structures and all those nice things, and lets you use C
libraries in your Python program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought, &amp;ldquo;Well, this sounds nice! Let&amp;rsquo;s write Python bindings for &lt;code&gt;libdpx&lt;/code&gt;! It
can&amp;rsquo;t be too hard!&amp;rdquo; I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;struggling-along:999b5b7440fa538dd5d40514f7485df6&#34;&gt;Struggling along&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve learned two major annoyances:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;calling-a-function-is-hard:999b5b7440fa538dd5d40514f7485df6&#34;&gt;Calling a function is hard.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation claims that that this is possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;from ctypes import *
import atexit

dpx = CDLL(&#39;libdpx.so&#39;)

def cleanup():
    dpx.dpx_cleanup()

dpx.dpx_init()
atexit.Register(cleanup)

peer = dpx.dpx_peer_new()

# do stuff with peer here
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;d be all nice and dandy, right? NOPE. Nowhere in the documentation does
ctypes seem to know what to do when you get a pointer back unless you
explicitly say it. It does say that return values would &amp;ldquo;assume to be int&amp;rdquo;. So
technically doing the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;peer = c_void_p(dpx.dpx_peer_new())
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;should work, right? Because c_void_p takes an integer argument, which comes out
of the function thanks to ctypes. And that integer argument is probably a
pointer, given the C return value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But nooo. &lt;em&gt;segfaults everywhere&lt;/em&gt;. I had to do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;dpn = dpx.dpx_peer_new
dpn.argtypes = []
dpn.restype = c_void_p

# now call it
peer = dpn()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;em&gt;every single function&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;i-apparently-cannot-work-with-pointers-nicely-with-ctypes:999b5b7440fa538dd5d40514f7485df6&#34;&gt;I apparently cannot work with pointers nicely with ctypes.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because, well.. Python seems to suck at pointer support. It&amp;rsquo;s understandable,
so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what I was expecting, but it&amp;rsquo;s still annoying when I do the
following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;dfn = dpx.dpx_frame_new
dfn.argtypes = [c_void_p]
dfn.restype = POINTER(CFRAME)
# POINTER(CFRAME) means the type is a pointer to a CFRAME
# CFRAME was a class derived from &amp;quot;Structure&amp;quot; that mimics dpx_frame in dpx.h

new_frame = dfn(None)

new_frame.payloadSize = 10
new_frame.payload = payload

channel.send(new_frame)
# Sending frame: 0 bytes...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only to realise that payloadSize that channel gets is size &lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt;. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s because the object &lt;code&gt;new_frame&lt;/code&gt; is a pointer object. It&amp;rsquo;s like any other
Python object, so I was actually setting the attributes &amp;lsquo;payloadSize&amp;rsquo; and
&amp;lsquo;payload&amp;rsquo; on the object itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then, how to get to the actual object?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t do &lt;code&gt;new_frame.contents&lt;/code&gt; like the docs say, because the docs also say
that Python will make a copy of the object. So that&amp;rsquo;s useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insted, I have to treat it like an array:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;actual_new_frame = new_frame[0]
actual_new_frame.payloadSize = 10
actual_new_frame.payload = payload

channel.send(new_frame)
# Sending frame: 10 bytes...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So those problems are solved, at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;so-you-re-happy-now:999b5b7440fa538dd5d40514f7485df6&#34;&gt;So you&amp;rsquo;re happy now?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope. See that cover image? Crashes everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same code that worked for the most core test case is now failing for the
next because &lt;code&gt;ctypes&lt;/code&gt; is passing invalid pointers (or I am).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to try my hand at making a Python extension instead. At least
I can code that in C&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT&lt;/strong&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;ve legitimately failed. It&amp;rsquo;s segfaulting because I&amp;rsquo;m cleaning up
structures prematurely. So therefore pointers that used to point to valid stuff
no longer do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I need to take shots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;where-is-your-code-so-i-can-laugh-at-it:999b5b7440fa538dd5d40514f7485df6&#34;&gt;Where is your code so I can laugh at it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By all means, please do! #ctypestruggles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s living &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robxu9/duplex/tree/dev_libtask_again&#34;&gt;in a branch of duplex right now&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Blog.</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/07/hello-blog./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/07/hello-blog./</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Welp, I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s about time that I made an actual blog on my actual domain.
Whee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a list of projects I wanted to do in the future - kinda like my personal
project collection. When I actually compiled the list, though, it started to
become a bit unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robxu9/uitest&#34;&gt;uitest&lt;/a&gt; - UI testing via VNC connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Minequest/gomq&#34;&gt;gomq&lt;/a&gt; - MineQuest, written in Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robxu9/kahinah&#34;&gt;kahinah&lt;/a&gt; - OpenMandriva&amp;rsquo;s QA Bot, which
needs a rewrite (codenamed &lt;em&gt;v4&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aye - a DO API client in Go (like tugboat)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gnome 3.12 updates for OpenMandriva, which are like half-finished now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robxu9/duplex&#34;&gt;duplex&lt;/a&gt; - message queue RPC but also
streaming i/o and peering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new live cd tool for OpenMandriva Lx (because livecd-creator is bleh)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zypper instead of urpmi for OpenMandriva Lx (which means I have to PR zypper
with support for hdlists)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trying my hand at writing an automated RPM build system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a lot. In reality, I&amp;rsquo;m only maintaining &lt;code&gt;kahinah&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;duplex&lt;/code&gt;, and then
splitting my time between gnome 3.12 updates and &lt;code&gt;uitest&lt;/code&gt;. The next to come
would probably be &lt;code&gt;aye&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;zypper&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;gomq&lt;/code&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m the naughty child with my hand in the cookie jar
trying to figure out which cookie to grab before mother comes back (read:
life takes over everything again).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eh. We&amp;rsquo;ll see, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-snippet-of-today:97f6c50ee355e8ed2cdf4e3f738c409d&#34;&gt;Code snippet of today&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got duplex as a shared library working, but that&amp;rsquo;s under a separate
branch for now because I want to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;. So, I&amp;rsquo;m writing
Python2 bindings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;from ctypes import *
dpx = CDLL(&#39;libdpx.so&#39;)

print dpx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^ That finally works. Thank god.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hey-i-m-robert:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Hey, I&amp;rsquo;m Robert.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a student, programmer, musician, and an avid newsreader. It&amp;rsquo;s a strange
combination, but it seems to all pull together in ways that surprise even
myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My website is just a small view into the random thoughts that flow across
my mind. I blog (when I remember to) about things from student life, to
programming in C, Go, and Java, some of the music I&amp;rsquo;ve liked lately (which
also changes wildly), and sometimes my thoughts on the latest news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find links to my Github and Twitter at the bottom of this page,
as well as my email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;student-life:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Student Life&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much to say here. I&amp;rsquo;m a student. I can be incredibly busy (or incredibly
lazy - they&amp;rsquo;re two sides of the same coin, right?). And clearly
I&amp;rsquo;m expected to be studying as hard as I can, without any free time, and
apply to the 1,000+ internships that are there so I can achieve success. /s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do study quite a bit, but I do try to take the time to relax a bit. And so
you&amp;rsquo;ll probably find me on IRC or some other social medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, those unfinished internship applications&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;programming:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Programming&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m one of the few people who codes in C - and possibly enjoys it. Does that
make me a masochist? One of my previous mentors thought so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides C, the majority of my coding goes towards making small utilities to
make my life easier, and coding in Go(lang). Go is an amazing language that
I have grown to love, and compromises a good portion of my projects nowadays.
At DigitalOcean and Glider Labs, I worked on many projects in Go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s Java. Java is the language which I have used most in the academic
world&amp;hellip; because it&amp;rsquo;s still on the curriculum. But I find it incredibly useful
as a learning language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve dabbled in Ruby and Rust. I feel that I&amp;rsquo;m not good enough to call myself
competent by any means, but some people have challenged me on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;musician:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Musician&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I play the Violin (and used to play the Piano), though I have to admit that
lately I&amp;rsquo;ve not been practicing any instrument. It&amp;rsquo;s a shortage of time, but
I want to come back to it sometime and hopefully not have forgotten like 10
years of skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someone asked me if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever done music via something like FL Studio. My
answer to that lies in my grade in Computer Music, which ended up in a B-.
(My last homework was done on a bus from New York to Washington, DC - you can
imagine the headache I was dealing with and the resulting piece of shite).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I listen to music. Things like Google Play All Access and Spotify Premium are
godsends to me. Additionally, I do buy albums of artists that I really really
love. It feels a bit more&amp;hellip; personal, you know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The type of music definitely changes. It can sway from dubstep to trance to
pop to rock to heavy metal to trance again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;news:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;News&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone walks in when I&amp;rsquo;m having a bit of spare time, they&amp;rsquo;ll be treated to
a bizarre sight of me watching something like BBC News or Sky News. I enjoy
keeping up with the news, and while a lot of it does not have that much of
an impact on my daily life (unless I&amp;rsquo;m watching something like NBC4), I find
it&amp;hellip; interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>