<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musings on Robert Xu</title>
    <link>https://www.robxu9.com/categories/musings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Musings on Robert Xu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2014-2015 Robert Xu. All Rights Reserved. Content not indicative of any addl party.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 03:17:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.robxu9.com/categories/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>where have I been all summer?</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/where-have-i-been-all-summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 03:17:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/where-have-i-been-all-summer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering why all the posts have suddenly appeared, the answer is
that I&amp;rsquo;ve finally achieved peak boredom level that I need to write on my blog
again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was quick. I just flew in from Seattle today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t obvious from the description, I just finished an internship
this past week. I already find myself wishing I could be back at my internship
with Amazon - it was amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked with Fulfillment by Amazon on Global Selling - and what an experience!
It gave me the insight into how to interact with business and develop solutions
that make sense, are maintainable, and can provide long term reliability. I got
a lot of good advice and criticism, and I would be lying if I said I didn&amp;rsquo;t
want to work there again - I&amp;rsquo;d love to. (But I&amp;rsquo;m doing a MBA programme that
will take next year&amp;rsquo;s summer away from me&amp;hellip; ARGH. HARD CHOICES)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seattle itself was wonderful. I think the key thing here is that it&amp;rsquo;s not hot
as hell the majority of the time, it&amp;rsquo;s a relaxing place, and it&amp;rsquo;s not humid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not humid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you realise how strange that is, coming from the east coast? It&amp;rsquo;s
mind-boggling. This past week was around the mid-60s and lower-70s - what great
weather!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from that, the general environment is great, the traffic is &lt;em&gt;loads&lt;/em&gt; better
than the east coast (I-5 is bad? Hah. Haven&amp;rsquo;t seen I-95, huh?), and it&amp;rsquo;s such a
nice place to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a bunch of cool roomies too, which made it even better. Made a lot of cool
friends &amp;ndash; wonder if we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to keep in touch. It&amp;rsquo;d definitely be fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, completely worth the experience. &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; would do again, but &lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; maybe
shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use ABODA. I think I might want to rent next time I go there. (But
then again, all the interns were in one place&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tl;dr A+ would do again&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new domains</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/new-domains/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 03:11:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/08/new-domains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past two months I have expanded my domain acquisitions. I now own
&lt;strong&gt;rxu.io&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;rxu.tech&lt;/strong&gt;, but I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly have too much of a clue with
what to do with them. Yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thinking that I&amp;rsquo;ll be making &lt;strong&gt;rxu.io&lt;/strong&gt; my personal homepage site - some
nice one page with links to all my profiles, resumes, this blog, etc; and
&lt;strong&gt;rxu.tech&lt;/strong&gt; a listing of projects that I am or were involved with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I am completely open to other ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cloudflare&#39;d</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/03/cloudflared/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 22:11:30 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/03/cloudflared/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My website was just cloudflare&amp;rsquo;d today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, this means that I&amp;rsquo;ve switched nameservers (again), from
DigitalOcean to CloudFlare. The main reason for that is because of
CloudFlare&amp;rsquo;s free https support, which I use in tandem with Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Yes, no https on robxu9.com severely irked me.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with new mail hosting lately, so
I&amp;rsquo;ve been switching mail providers like&amp;hellip; every other week. Still self
hosting in the end, but I just wanted to remark on a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zentyal&lt;/strong&gt;: I &lt;em&gt;really really really really really really&lt;/em&gt; wanted to
like you like Carly Rae Jepsen&amp;rsquo;s new obsession. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. You have a
strange number of problems, your general configuration screen doesn&amp;rsquo;t work
(&amp;ldquo;missing parameter: id&amp;rdquo;???), and it was an overall mess. But your ability
to mimic Exchange and also put together Mail, Contacts, and Calendar all
in one with OpenChange and SoGo was really appealing. Unfortunately, errors
aren&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mailinabox.email&lt;/strong&gt;: I mentioned that I wanted to use CloudFlare, right?
Mail-in-a-Box is really insistent that you use its internal DNS, and if you
don&amp;rsquo;t, add 100000000 DNS records to CloudFlare instead. That&amp;rsquo;s not really an
issue, but then bind9 refused to resolve any DNS requests, and I gave up there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yunohost&lt;/strong&gt;: I really wish I had a picture of that meme right now. But this
is what I&amp;rsquo;m currently using now, after three weeks (Mail-in-a-Box is actually
still up on my other VPS, but that&amp;rsquo;s going down as soon as DNS propagates).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; nice to have a tiled welcome screen and something that seems to
Just Work &amp;trade; after so long. Although, I have to admit, Dovecot ran out of
epoll handlers and that left me stumped, but a reboot solved that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should go study for CSE 320 now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>welp</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/02/welp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 23:46:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/02/welp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That was quick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have I been up to? Things I&amp;rsquo;ve done lately include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;studying for CSE 320, which is System Architecture. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m slow on
the uptake with this class, whatnot with muxes and ALUs&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;working on CSE 306, which is implementing a simple &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; without libc. So
just Linux system calls. Not bad, just time consuming. Also I gave up trying
to make descriptive errors and just dumped &lt;code&gt;errno.h&lt;/code&gt; into a switch statement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I should probably do the Ethics project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beat Tales of Symphonia, Tales of Symphonia: Knights of Ratatosk, and started
Tales of the Abyss, then realised that I actually have homework to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Had an Amazon interview. This was my first real interview in a &lt;strong&gt;LONG&lt;/strong&gt; time,
and I&amp;rsquo;m not so certain I ace&amp;rsquo;d it. It was an experience, but it took my brain
way too long to warm up and I think that cost me. I think I missed a Big-O
notation and I definitely forgot about Kruskal&amp;rsquo;s algorithm. Shit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Went to Boston for ECAASU 2015! Here&amp;rsquo;s a tip: don&amp;rsquo;t drive in Boston. The
roads make no sense whatsoever (they&amp;rsquo;re like downtown Manhattan), and the
random forks and roundabouts hurt my head.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s more happening soon, but I gotta survive until at least Spring Break&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>robxu9.com, take two</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/robxu9.com-take-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 22:48:42 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/robxu9.com-take-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never had the time to really blog about things in length after I left
DigitalOcean. I guess I felt like it was time consuming and such effort could
better be spent sleeping or coding or something along the lines of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then school came around and I was thrown into the chaos that is the fall
semester of university, and I never had a chance to step back from all the
craziness that followed and put my thoughts together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now here we are. It&amp;rsquo;s 2015, almost 6 months since my last blog post.
I&amp;rsquo;ve resolved to take more time out to reflect on what&amp;rsquo;s been happening and
gather my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m therefore taking bets on how quickly this will fall apart. Minimum time
after I finish writing this post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Blog.</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/07/hello-blog./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2014/07/hello-blog./</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Welp, I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s about time that I made an actual blog on my actual domain.
Whee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a list of projects I wanted to do in the future - kinda like my personal
project collection. When I actually compiled the list, though, it started to
become a bit unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robxu9/uitest&#34;&gt;uitest&lt;/a&gt; - UI testing via VNC connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Minequest/gomq&#34;&gt;gomq&lt;/a&gt; - MineQuest, written in Go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robxu9/kahinah&#34;&gt;kahinah&lt;/a&gt; - OpenMandriva&amp;rsquo;s QA Bot, which
needs a rewrite (codenamed &lt;em&gt;v4&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aye - a DO API client in Go (like tugboat)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gnome 3.12 updates for OpenMandriva, which are like half-finished now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robxu9/duplex&#34;&gt;duplex&lt;/a&gt; - message queue RPC but also
streaming i/o and peering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a new live cd tool for OpenMandriva Lx (because livecd-creator is bleh)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;zypper instead of urpmi for OpenMandriva Lx (which means I have to PR zypper
with support for hdlists)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trying my hand at writing an automated RPM build system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a lot. In reality, I&amp;rsquo;m only maintaining &lt;code&gt;kahinah&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;duplex&lt;/code&gt;, and then
splitting my time between gnome 3.12 updates and &lt;code&gt;uitest&lt;/code&gt;. The next to come
would probably be &lt;code&gt;aye&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;zypper&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;gomq&lt;/code&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m the naughty child with my hand in the cookie jar
trying to figure out which cookie to grab before mother comes back (read:
life takes over everything again).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eh. We&amp;rsquo;ll see, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-snippet-of-today:97f6c50ee355e8ed2cdf4e3f738c409d&#34;&gt;Code snippet of today&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got duplex as a shared library working, but that&amp;rsquo;s under a separate
branch for now because I want to make sure it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt;. So, I&amp;rsquo;m writing
Python2 bindings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;from ctypes import *
dpx = CDLL(&#39;libdpx.so&#39;)

print dpx
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^ That finally works. Thank god.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>