<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>School on Robert Xu</title>
    <link>https://www.robxu9.com/categories/school/</link>
    <description>Recent content in School on Robert Xu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2014-2015 Robert Xu. All Rights Reserved. Content not indicative of any addl party.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 16:32:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.robxu9.com/categories/school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>graduating early</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/04/graduating-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 16:32:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/04/graduating-early/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s weird to think that only a few semesters ago, I was starting university.
But as I went into my advisor last week and sat down and went over my
coursework and transcript, I noticed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how many more classes
I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we both sat down and analysed what I had left to take, and what I was
planning to take. And we both came to the conclusion that I would be graduating
&lt;strong&gt;one year early&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people can only dream of doing this, and especially in Computer Science,
courses are rigirous enough to discourage people from taking too many classes
at one time, lest they be burnt grade-wise. (&lt;em&gt;stares at cse320&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for some reason, it worked out that I had 36 credits left to take - or 12
classes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing 5 classes per semester, not wanting to stress myself
out, but it looks like with 12 classes left, that&amp;rsquo;s about 2 semesters or 3
semesters, depending on how it&amp;rsquo;s partitioned. (There is an option to do
6-5-1, where the last credit is taken in the summer session and I graduate
officially in August, even though I go to the May ceremony, but I&amp;rsquo;m opting
to do the last credit before, so it&amp;rsquo;s 1-6-5.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And especially since I&amp;rsquo;m out of state, an additional semester isn&amp;rsquo;t really
worth it only for 4 credits money-wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a couple of options ahead of me. I guess I should start putting 2016
instead of 2017 in my graduation date for job applications, and I guess I should
look and see what I have in store for myself. Like, I want to get a degree for
a MBA in the near future, so maybe I could work on the MBA and graduate in 2017,
but it&amp;rsquo;s still all up in the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many choices. So many decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should update my resume. I lost my resume document, except I still have the
PDF, so I guess I have to recreate it&amp;hellip; again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>and now for something completely different</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/03/and-now-for-something-completely-different/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 20:28:53 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/03/and-now-for-something-completely-different/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s spring break, and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to finally have a week to kind of relax and
not worry about midterms as much (of course, I&amp;rsquo;m ignoring the fact that I have
a midterm in CSE306/Operating Systems next week), but it also gives the chance
to reflect and ask, &amp;ldquo;what the hell went wrong on Friday?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday was my CSE320/Computer Organization &amp;amp; Architecture midterm - a midterm
that currently has a 43% average and what the professor called &amp;ldquo;dismal scores
across the board&amp;rdquo;: so where did it all go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of debate recently in our class about what lengths a teacher
should go to help their students. I personally think that our professor is
doing a fine job, despite my own past grievances against her. She&amp;rsquo;s been
releasing practice problems, despite being under no obligation to do so; and
they&amp;rsquo;ve been helpful. Having TAs help our class (even though our class
should technically have no TAs) has also been a huge help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But while I seem to be satisfied, there are others who are starting to actively
rally the class against her teaching skills, despite the fact that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t
seem like many other of her previous classes have had as much trouble. So is it
just our class?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-difficult-question-of-what-teachers-should-be-doing:80f5062d88d9dcfdb5f1da7e32750f76&#34;&gt;The difficult question of what teachers should be doing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These teachers have a difficult job. Given a class of anywhere from 30 to 200
students (and even more for general education classes, where lecture halls
quickly fill to 500-1000 students), they have the insurmountable task of
teaching every single one of those students the skills they need to move on
to the next class. It&amp;rsquo;s sometimes an almost impossible task, regardless of the
class size, and yet they still plow on every single semester and try their
best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teachers are the best, simply for looking up in the face of all this pressure,
giving it the middle finger, and then proceeding (most of the time) to smash
expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work out? Teachers have readily gone out of their way
to provide extra material in the form of practice problems, review sessions,
lab sessions, better homework software, and more - and they&amp;rsquo;re not exactly
paid to do that, either. They could easily tell you that the textbook was
required for the course, so read the textbook and figure it out on your own
and stop by office hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, they go out of their way to do a whole lot more whenever possible,
and make sure that learning centres are open for other students to help as
well. Basically, all avenues as open as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-moment-the-students-begin-to-expect-extra-as-normal:80f5062d88d9dcfdb5f1da7e32750f76&#34;&gt;The moment the students begin to expect extra as &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the extra material seems to get mixed up as normal material.
Then what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s where the debate is - do teachers have an obligation to continue
doing these extra things for their classes if they&amp;rsquo;ve done it in the
past, or can they simply say no if it turns out to be untenable? Does it fall
to the students to make the extra material?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(sidenote: I will say it does fall to the student to take advantage of office
hours at the very minimum and study the normal material.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no ending to this blog post, because I can&amp;rsquo;t answer this question.
Maybe someone else can. Or can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue the discussion - comment below, or @robxu9 on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sophomore year, take two</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/sophomore-year-take-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 17:54:17 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/01/sophomore-year-take-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long story short:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CSE 306: Operating Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CSE 312: Ethics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CSE 320: System Architecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MEC 280: Pollution &amp;amp; Human Health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CCS 202: Film Genres&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I survive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>