<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Its Weird on Robert Xu</title>
    <link>https://www.robxu9.com/tags/its-weird/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Its Weird on Robert Xu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2014-2016 Robert Xu. All Rights Reserved. Content not indicative of any addl party.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 16:32:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.robxu9.com/tags/its-weird/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>graduating early</title>
      <link>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/04/graduating-early/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 16:32:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>me@robxu9.com (Robert Xu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.robxu9.com/2015/04/graduating-early/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s weird to think that only a few semesters ago, I was starting university.
But as I went into my advisor last week and sat down and went over my
coursework and transcript, I noticed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how many more classes
I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we both sat down and analysed what I had left to take, and what I was
planning to take. And we both came to the conclusion that I would be graduating
&lt;strong&gt;one year early&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people can only dream of doing this, and especially in Computer Science,
courses are rigirous enough to discourage people from taking too many classes
at one time, lest they be burnt grade-wise. (&lt;em&gt;stares at cse320&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for some reason, it worked out that I had 36 credits left to take - or 12
classes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing 5 classes per semester, not wanting to stress myself
out, but it looks like with 12 classes left, that&amp;rsquo;s about 2 semesters or 3
semesters, depending on how it&amp;rsquo;s partitioned. (There is an option to do
6-5-1, where the last credit is taken in the summer session and I graduate
officially in August, even though I go to the May ceremony, but I&amp;rsquo;m opting
to do the last credit before, so it&amp;rsquo;s 1-6-5.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And especially since I&amp;rsquo;m out of state, an additional semester isn&amp;rsquo;t really
worth it only for 4 classes money-wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a couple of options ahead of me. I guess I should start putting 2016
instead of 2017 in my graduation date for job applications, and I guess I should
look and see what I have in store for myself. Like, I want to get a degree for
a MBA in the near future, so maybe I could work on the MBA and graduate in 2017,
but it&amp;rsquo;s still all up in the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many choices. So many decisions. I&amp;rsquo;m scared I&amp;rsquo;ll make the wrong one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should update my resume. I lost my resume document, except I still have the
PDF, so I guess I have to recreate it&amp;hellip; again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>